

TONIA GONZALEZ

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

503- 473-4519 | toniagonzalez.design@gmail.com Website: https://toniagonzalez.com Github: https://github.com/toniagonzalez

LANGUAGES & TECHNOLOGIES

AWS, GraphQL, Git, Kafka,
Basic Unix, Java, HTML5,
CSS3, JavaScript
(Typescript, Node.js, Express,
React.js) SQL, PostgreSQL,
PHP/Wordpress, Drupal,
Terraform/HCL

DESIGN SKILLS

Responsive Web Design

Sketch & Figma

UI Prototyping & Wireframing

Adobe Suite programs (Illustrator, Photoshop, XD)

PERSONAL SKILLS

Excellent verbal and written communication skills with people from diverse backgrounds and experience levels.

Ability to work collaboratively in a distributed team and also be an independent self-starter

Can effectively multi-task while completing projects fully and on time

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - New Relic

JULY 2020 - Current

- o Internationalization of New Relic new user signup interface.
- Leveraged UX research to increase user utilization of the platform by building an onboarding checklist.
- Collaborated with product and design to create an observability maturity feature that gives users insights into alerting and asset management.

Drupal Publishing CMS (Volunteer) - Bitch Magazine

SEPTEMBER 2020 - JUNE 2021

- o Prepared new drupal nodes for print and online article content.
- Enabled SEO tagging for online articles.
- Added captions and alt text for online article images.

UI/UX Consultant - Site Redesign - Poley Creative

- o Assessed initial site functionality & researched tools for lead generation.
- o Produced basic wireframe & full prototype for a website redesign.

Web Developer (Freelance) - Custom CSS - NextUp

 Provided branded layout for nonprofit - NextUp's youth voter registration initiative to be used on the "Rock the Vote" CMS.

CERTIFICATION

AWS — Certificate, Cloud Practitioner

NOVEMBER 2021

EDUCATION

Treehouse — Tech Degree, Front End & Full Stack JavaScript
MARCH 2018 - AUGUST 2019

Portland State University, OR — B.A. in Arabic, Certificate in Global Studies

Graduated Summa Cum Laude

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Printmaking, Birding, Gardening, Astronomy, Baking